<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ruby on fabiorehm.com</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/tags/ruby/</link><description>Recent content in ruby on fabiorehm.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/fgrehm">Fabio Rehm&lt;/a> 2013-2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabiorehm.com/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Devstep: Development environments powered by Docker and Buildpacks</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/08/26/devstep-development-environments-powered-by-docker-and-buildpacks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/08/26/devstep-development-environments-powered-by-docker-and-buildpacks/</guid><description>Devstep is a relatively new project that I I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on since February 2014 and had its second release last friday. On its current state, Devstep is a dead simple, no frills development environment builder powered by Docker and the buildpack abstraction that is based around a simple (yet ambitious) goal:
I want to git clone and run a single command to hack on any software project.
Intrigued? Check out the demo below of my &amp;ldquo;canonical Discourse example&amp;rdquo; and read on for more.</description></item><item><title>Set the default Vagrant provider from your Vagrantfile</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/11/12/set-the-default-vagrant-provider-from-your-vagrantfile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/11/12/set-the-default-vagrant-provider-from-your-vagrantfile/</guid><description>There are times that you might need / want to use a specific provider for your Vagrant boxes that differs from VirtualBox or whatever provider you have set on your VAGRANT_DEFAULT_PROVIDER environmental variable.
For experienced Ruby users this might seem something trivial to do but since Vagrant&amp;rsquo;s community is made of people from many different programming languages background, I thought it would be nice to share this little trick I find useful when I need to make sure the VMs goes up with the right provider.</description></item><item><title>Announcing letter_opener_web 1.0</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/01/22/announcing-letter_opener_web-1-0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/01/22/announcing-letter_opener_web-1-0/</guid><description>One of the things I missed the most after going 100% on Vagrant was the ability to preview Rails apps sent mails on my browser. I got used to the awesome letter_opener gem which depends on launchy to fire up a new browser window with the email preview instead of sending. As launchy on its own wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to open up a browser window on the host machine from the guest box, I started to look around for alternatives and wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find something else that worked for me.</description></item><item><title>100% on Vagrant</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/01/17/100-percent-on-vagrant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/01/17/100-percent-on-vagrant/</guid><description>Last year I heard a lot about Vagrant and even though I had the chance to play with it, performance was always an issue that prevented me from doing 100% of my development work from a VM. By december, when my laptop started acting weird (and eventually died) I decided that my next computer would have as much cores and RAM that I could afford. I looked at a few different options and ended up getting a Dell Inspiron 15R SE with a Core I7 that has 4 cores and 8 threads and 8 Gb RAM.</description></item></channel></rss>