<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>golang on fabiorehm.com</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/tags/golang/</link><description>Recent content in golang on fabiorehm.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/fgrehm">Fabio Rehm&lt;/a> 2013-2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fabiorehm.com/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trigger notify-send across the network using HTTP</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/10/12/trigger-notify-send-across-the-network-using-http/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/10/12/trigger-notify-send-across-the-network-using-http/</guid><description>Last week I cut the first release of notify-send-http, a tool for triggering notify-send across the network using HTTP. Useful for forwarding notifications from local VMs / Containers to your own computer. It even supports notification icons!
Tested on Ubuntu 14.04 only
Why? Because I do all of my dev work on virtualized environments and I use guard quite a lot to keep my Ruby tests running when files get changed.</description></item><item><title>Devstep updates</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/09/25/devstep-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/09/25/devstep-updates/</guid><description>The third release of the Devstep Docker image came out last night along with a brand new Golang CLI featuring some very nice improvements and new functionality. The CHANGELOG is here and on this post I&amp;rsquo;ll cover some exciting new stuff I was able to get in place.
Docker image updates Starting with the base image updates, the 0.2.0 release dropped from 1.168GB down to 867.7MB MB representing a ~25% reduction on disk usage.</description></item><item><title>Get notified of long running CLI tasks completion with 'lmk'</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/08/09/get-notified-of-long-running-cli-tasks-completion-with-lmk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2014/08/09/get-notified-of-long-running-cli-tasks-completion-with-lmk/</guid><description>lmk is a simple command line tool written in Go that I released last February. I wrote it to draw my attention to a terminal when some long command finishes running.
WTF?!? Yeah, it may sound silly but how often do you run a command that you know that takes a lot of time to complete, you go do something else and forget that the command was running? Even worse, what about when you get side tracked for a bit longer than you should and when you Alt+Tab to check if the command has finished it actually errored along the way?</description></item><item><title>Meet Viewdocs</title><link>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/11/12/meet-viewdocs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fabiorehm.com/blog/2013/11/12/meet-viewdocs/</guid><description>Last week @progrium striked again with one more great example of how we should strive for keeping things simple. Five months after releasing Dokku which is a Docker powered mini-Heroku written in around 100 lines of Bash, he has just open sourced viewdocs:
As with Dokku, the project is pretty small and (as of this writing) converts ~200 lines of Golang code into a powerful tool for small to medium sized open source projects hosted on GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>